So once we've inserted the
chart, it's time to look at some
formatting options for the chart.
Now, the first one that I would select
is, if I highlight the chart, and it
brings up the chart style menu bar.
And if I look along there, I can just move
my mouse along the different chart styles
till I find one that I'm happy with.
And in this instance, I'm just going
to stay with the first one, which
was style one, the default style.
And in addition to that, I
can also change the colour.
So this will allow me to change
the colours of the actual
columns within the chart.
But again, I'm just going to stay
with the blue for the moment.
Now, as well as that, as you can
see, the chart has a title and
that's because I included the total
sales heading when I did the actual
selection of the data for the chart.
And, I also need to
indicate what these are.
So at the moment the title is total
sales, but if I wanted to indicate on
the axis titles, what that was, I would
need to go to the chart elements button.
Now, if I click on that, it
gives me a range of options.
So the axis titles are already there.
If I take those off.
That's all that would be displayed.
So if I click that back on, it's showing
the vertical and the horizontal axis.
So it's giving me that information, but
I may also want to have axis titles on.
So as you can see, when I move
my mouse over axis titles, it
adds two little dialog boxes.
So I click on that and you can
see there I can type in there.
So in that one there, what I would want
to type is that is the total sales.
And press enter.
And this one here would be product.
So if I just, as you can see, I'm
typing this into the formula bar,
but that is where it will appear.
So I type product and it
is then changed to product.
So once you've got that on,
you've got a clear indication
of what that information is.
So I may want to add
the actual data labels.
So if I selected data labels, that
would then give me an even clearer
indication of what the figures were.
So I can see from the figures on
the left, that it is between 350
and 400 or between 400 and 450.
But to make it clear, I can actually add
the data labels so people can see at a
glance exactly what those figures were.
So now that I've applied that formatting,
I have the total sales text along the
left-hand side and have the product
along the bottom so it's making it
clear exactly what is being displayed.
But I may also need a legend.
Now because there is only one element
of data and that is basically the actual
total sales, I don't need a legend, but
if, for example, I had have created the
chart and it was the product and the
January sales, February sales, March
sales for each of the products, it
would then be a case that I would need a
legend to differentiate between the two.
So if I needed to add a legend,
I would simply click on the chart
element button and then select legend.
And as you can see, as I only have the
total sales it is only showing that, but
if I had the total income included or I
had the January sales, February sales,
it would allow a different colour for each
of those, which would then be shown as
a different colour on the legends, which
would again, allow you to identify exactly
what was being shown within the chart.